Lesson 16. Mary had a little lamb. Mary and her husband, Demetri, lived in the tiny village of
第16课。玛丽有一点羔羊。玛丽和她的丈夫德米特里（Demetri）住在一个小村庄
Peracura in southern Greece. One of Mary's prized possessions was a little white lamb which her
希腊南部的Peracura。玛丽珍贵的财产之一是一个白色的小羔羊
tie: v.   拴，系
husband had given her. She kept it tied to a tree in a field during the day and went to fetch it
丈夫给了她。她白天把它绑在田野里的一棵树上，然后去拿它
every evening. One evening, however, the lamb was missing, the rope had been cut, so it was obvious
每天晚上。但是，一个晚上，羔羊丢失了，绳子被切了，很明显
that the lamb had been stolen. When Demetri came in from the fields, his wife told him what had
羔羊被盗了。当德米特（Demetri）从田地进来时，他的妻子告诉他
happened. Demetri at once set out to find the thief. He knew it would not prove difficult in such a
发生了。Demetri立即着手找到小偷。他知道这在这样的人中并不困难
theft: n.   偷盗行为，偷盗案
small village. After telling several of his friends about the theft, Demetri found out that his
小村庄。在告诉了他的几个朋友有关盗窃的信息之后，德米特利发现他的
neighbor, Aleco, had suddenly acquired a new lamb. Demetri immediately went to Aleco's house and
邻居Aleco突然获得了一个新的羔羊。Demetri立即去了Aleco的家，
accuse: v.   指控
angrily accused him of stealing the lamb. He told him he had better return it where he would call
愤怒地指责他偷了羊羔。他告诉他，他最好返回他会打电话的地方
the police. Aleco denied taking it and led Demetri into his backyard. It was true that he had just
警察。Aleco否认将其带到他的后院。的确，他只是
bought a lamb. He explained, but his lamb was black. A shamed of having acted so rashly.
买了羊肉。他解释说，但他的羔羊是黑色的。如此轻率的行为感到羞耻。
accuse: v.   指控, apologize: v.   道歉
Demetri apologized to Aleco for having accused him. While they were talking it began to rain and
Demetri向Aleco道歉，因为他指责他。当他们说话时，下雨了
Demetri stayed in Aleco's house until the rain stopped. When he went outside half an hour later,
德米特里（Demetri）留在亚历科（Aleco）的房子里，直到下雨停止。半小时后他出门时，
dye: v.   染
he was astonished to find the little black lamb was almost white. Its wool, which had been dyed black,
他惊讶地发现黑羔羊几乎是白色的。它的羊毛被染成黑色，
had been washed clean by the rain.
被雨水洗净了。